<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Monmouth's CSSE news feed</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx</link><description>The latest news about CSSE Department at Monmouth</description><generator>PyRSS2Gen-1.1.0</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>2016 High School Programming Contest</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#hsprogcontest2016</link><description>The CSSE department and IEEE/ACM Student Chapter hosted the 2016 High School Programming Competition on Friday March 4, 2016. Twenty t</description></item><item><title>IEEE/ACM Student Chapter Receives NCWIT Student Seed Fund Gift from Google.org</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#googleaward2016</link><description>Monmouth University's IEEE/ACM Student Chapter has been awarded a National Center for Women and Information Technology (NCWIT) Student</description></item><item><title>Faculty Member and 5 Students Attend 2015 Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing Conference in Houston, TX</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#gracehopper2015</link><description>For the second year in a row, Monmouth faculty and students have been part of the world’s largest gathering of women technologists a</description></item><item><title>Inaugural High School Programming Contest</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#hsprogcontest2015</link><description>The Monmouth University IEEE/ACM Student Chapter is hosting their inaugural High School Programming Competition on Thursday May 14, 20</description></item><item><title>CSSE Faculty and Students Participating in Hour of Code</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#hourofcode2014</link><description>Monmouth University’s Computer Science and Software Engineering Department is encouraging everyone to join in on the largest learn</description></item><item><title>CSSE Juniors Win Awards At Second Annual Marathon Hackathon</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#hackathon0614</link><description>Two CSSE Juniors, Justin Schlemm and Taylor Klodowski recently earned a second-place award at Marathon Data Systems’ second annua</description></item><item><title>IEEE/ACM Student Chapter attends IEEE Region 1 Student Conference at NJIT</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#ieee0314</link><description>On March 29th, 2014, the IEEE/ACM student chapter of Monmouth University attended the IEEE Region 1 Student Conference at NJIT.  At</description></item><item><title>CS Grad Student Featured in Faces of Monmouth</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#delfattore1</link><description>Christopher Del Fattore (BS in CS, 2013) has a featured profile in Faces of Monmouth. As part of his Spring 2013 senior project, Ch</description></item><item><title>CSSE Department to Offer New Master of Science in Information Systems Degree</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#msis</link><description>The Monmouth University Board of Trustees has approved the Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering's proposed Master o</description></item><item><title>Two Teams of CS Seniors Receive Dean's Award of Excellence in Undergraduate Research</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#deansAwardSp13</link><description>The following two teams of CS Seniors have received the School of Science Dean's Award of Excellence in Undergraduate Research in i</description></item><item><title>Team of Current and Former CSSE Dept. Students Wins 24-Hour Hackathon To Benefit Jersey Shore Recovery From Super Storm Sandy</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#hackathon0413</link><description>On April 28-29, three of our Monmouth CSSE students participated in--and won--a 24-hour Hackathon called the Jersey Shore Comeback-</description></item><item><title>Software Engineering Dept. Graduate Reflects On MU Experience</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#vDesai</link><description>Software Engineering Dept. graduate (2012) Vishruti Desai wrote a graduation essay that appeared in the Asbury Park Press on Janu</description></item><item><title>Software Engineering Dept. alumnus named 'Modern-Day Technology Leader'</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#jWormley</link><description>US Army CERDEC Release No.: 130102
14 January 2013
Monmouth University alumnus named 'Modern-Day Technology Leader'
ABERDEEN P</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Publishes A New Book</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#mob010413</link><description>"Handbook of Green Information and Communication Systems" 

(Excerpt:)
Monmouth University is proud to announce that Dr. Mohammad S.</description></item><item><title>CSSE Department Hosts its 1st Annual First Year Students Breakfast </title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#firstYearBreakfast2012</link><description>The CSSE Department held its 1st Annual First Year Students Breakfast on Tuesday, Sept 11. First Year Computer Science and Softwa</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Wins Prestigious SCS Presidential Award</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#mob032912</link><description>(Excerpt:)
Monmouth University is very pleased to announce that Dr. Mohammad S. Obaidat, professor of computer science and software e</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Featured In Asbury Park Press Article On Digital Reading Devices</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#mobApp0312</link><description>Computer Science and Software Engineering&amp;#160;Professor Mohammad S. Obaidat was featured in the Asbury Park Press on 12.
(Excerpt:)</description></item><item><title>CS Alumnus Featured in School of Science Newsletter</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#barnathan1</link><description>Michael Barnathan (BS in CS, 2006) is the featured alumnus in the Spring 2012 issue of Science Buzz, the School of Science e-news</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Publishes Two Books, Gives Two Keynote Speeches, and Receives an Award</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#obidat1</link><description>&amp;#160;

Monmouth University is proud to announce that Professor Mohammad S. Obaidat (IEEE Fellow and SCS Fellow) of the Department of</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Receives "Best Paper Award" at IEEE International Conference</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#obidat2</link><description>Professor Mohammad S. Obaidat received the Best Paper Award from the 2011 Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</description></item><item><title>CS Alumnus Successfully Defends Ph.D. Thesis</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#rkhPhD</link><description>We congratulate Raffi Khatchadourian, who completed his B.S. in Computer Science at Monmouth in 2004. Raffi has successfully defe</description></item><item><title>Professor Paparella Visits Abu Dhabi in Her Role as Executive Director of the International Council in Innovation in Higher Education Conference</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#mpaAbuDhabi</link><description>Professor Maureen Paparella presented Dr. Youssef Shatilla, a professor of nuclear engineering and associate dean of the Masdar I</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Gives Main Distinguished Keynote Speech at GreenCom 2010 and CPSCom 2010 in China and Receives Prestigious IEEE Outstanding Leadership Award </title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#mobGreenCom10</link><description>Professor Mohammad S. Obaidat gave the main Distinguished Keynote Speech at the Joint 2010 IEEE/ACM International Conference on</description></item><item><title>Professor Milewski Receives Bright Idea Award</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#amiBrightIdea</link><description>Professor Allen Milewski received a Bright Idea Award for co-authoring the paper titled "Occurrence and effects of leader deleg</description></item><item><title>Professor Wang Visits Schools in Hyderabad, India</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#jwaHyder</link><description>Professor Jay Wang, Chair of the Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering, visited Hyderabad, India for student re</description></item><item><title>Professor Kretsch Gives Presentation at the Science &amp;amp; Engineering Learning Center in Manalapan H.S.</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#jkrSELC</link><description>Professor Jamie Kretsch attended an Open House at the Science &amp;amp; Engineering Learning Center (SELC) in Manalapan H.S. (Freehold</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Gives Main Distinguished Keynote Speeches at Well-Known International Conferences and Chairs Major International Conferences</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#mobsu2010</link><description>Professor Mohammad S. Obaidat gave the main Distinguished Keynote Speech at the IEEE International Conference on Information Te</description></item><item><title>CS-298: Summer Study Abroad Class in Xi'an, China, June 4-15, 2010</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#cs298su10</link><description>A special topic summer travel class, CS-298 Technology in China, took place in Xi'an, China, from June 4 through 15. The class was ho</description></item><item><title>Summer Computer Camp at Monmouth University </title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#compcamp2010</link><description>For the sixth summer in a row, Monmouth University has offered a cutting-edge Computer Camp for students in middle school and high sc</description></item><item><title>Professor McDonald Publishes Book Titled &lt;em&gt;Managing the Development of Software Intensive Systems&lt;/em&gt;, John Wiley &amp;amp; Sons, Inc.</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#jmcWiley2010</link><description>The book is a primer on managing software-based development projects and complex software/hardware systems. The book discusses the ap</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Publishes Book Titled &lt;em&gt;Fundamentals of Performance Evaluation of Computer and Telecommunication Systems&lt;/em&gt;, John Wiley &amp;amp; Sons.</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#mobWiley2010</link><description>The book, co-authored by Dr. Noureddine A. Boudriga, is considered the only singular, all-encompassing textbook on state-of-the-art t</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Gives Main Distinguished Keynote Speech at IEEE ICUT 2009 Conference in Japan, and Invited Distinguished Keynote Speech at Korean Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#mobIcut</link><description>Professor Mohammad S. Obaidat gave the main Distinguished Keynote Speech at the IEEE International Conference on Ubiquitous Informa</description></item><item><title>CS511 Students Produce Digital Campus Map</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#mkocs511</link><description>A group of students from Professor Kosaka's CS511 Technical Communication class has produced a digital campus map that is integrated w</description></item><item><title>Computer Science and Software Engineering Dept. Signs Memorandum of Understanding with Xi'an University of Posts and Telecommunication</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#MOUXian</link><description>&amp;#160;Xiaozheng Wen of Xi'an
&amp;#160;University

On December 5, 2009, Xiaozheng Wen, Vice President of Xi'an University of Posts and</description></item><item><title>Computer Science and Software Engineering Dept. Signs Memorandum of Understanding with St. Peter's Engineering College in Hyderabad, India</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#MOUStPete</link><description>Engineering College and
Dr. Robert McCaig

On December 4, 2009, Mr. Vijaypaul Reddy, Secretary/Director of St. Peters Engineering</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Wins IEEE GLOBECOM 2009 Best Paper Award for Paper Titled "&lt;em&gt;Cross-Layer Based Data Management in Mobile Ad Hoc Networks"&lt;/em&gt; </title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#MobGlobeCom</link><description>The paper has been accepted in the IEEE GLOBCOM 2009 Conference, Honolulu, Hawaii, November 30 through December 4, 2009. This is one o</description></item><item><title>Professor Wang Visits Five Institutions in Four Cities in China for Student Recruitment and Student and Faculty Exchange.</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#JwaChina</link><description>From October 22 through November 1, 2009, Professor Jiacun Wang, Chair of Department of Computer Science and Software Engineering, vis</description></item><item><title>Professor Kosaka Gives Talk on the "Analysis of Wishes" at Computer Science Academy, Freehold High School.</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#MkoFreehold</link><description>Professor Michiko Kosaka gave a talk to the students at the Computer Science Academy, Freehold High School, on October 26. The talk wa</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Receives SCS Most Prestigious McLeod's Award for Outstanding Technical Contribution and Services to Modeling and Computer Simulation</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#MObMcLeod</link><description>Professor Mohammad S. Obaidat has been awarded the Society for Modeling and Simulation International (SCS) most prestigious award, the</description></item><item><title>Professor Obaidat Elected President of the Society for Modeling and Simulation International and Received Best Paper Award</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#MObSCSPres</link><description>Professor Mohammad S. Obaidat was elected the new president of the Society for Modeling and Simulation International (SCS). In additio</description></item><item><title>Departments of Computer Science and Software Engineering Merged</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#CSSEMerger</link><description>To better manage and market our CS and SE programs, the Department of Computer Science and Department of Software Engineering were for</description></item><item><title>Graduate Program Changes Starting Academic Year 2009</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#GradChanges2009</link><description>We would like to detail changes to the Graduate CS Program starting in the Fall 2009 semester.
The MS Degree will now require 30 cred</description></item><item><title>Significant CS Program Changes Starting Academic Year 2008</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#Changes</link><description>We would like to announce two recent program changes starting in the Fall 2008 semester.
First, our initial instructional programming</description></item><item><title>CS Students Present Research At Seventh Annual STE Student Research Conference</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#Conference</link><description>Two CompSci students presented posters at the Seventh Annual STE Student Research Conference. Julian Montefusco, a M.S. student, prese</description></item><item><title>CS Alumnus Makes Successful Ph.D. Dissertation Defense</title><link>http://www.monmouth.edu/school-of-science/news-and-events.aspx#sObeidatPhD</link><description>Congratulations to Suhaib Obeidat, who completed his M.S. in Computer Science at Monmouth in 2001 under the supervision of Dr. Obaida</description></item></channel></rss>